Dobromir Marinov

Colchester, United Kingdom

(+44) 7599-943662

mr.d.marinov@gmail.com

https://dmarinov.com/

Personal Profile

I am a software engineer with 3 years of professional experience. My main programming languages are Python and Java and my research interests lie in machine learning and software engineering. I am an EU citizen and I am eligible to work and study in the UK.

Employment

MSX International

Software Engineer (Data science department)

Colchester, United Kingdom

June 2018 - Present

- Development and deployment of machine learning models for predictive analytics in the automotive industry.
- Building microservices.
- Python, R, AWS, Docker, Nginx, Redshift, Exasol, LATEX.

MSX International

Software Developer

- Working in a team developing web applications.
- Java EE, SpringMVC, Liferay 6/7, Oracle, Jboss.
- PL/SQL, Hibernate, Freemarker, Gradle, Selenium.

Colchester, United Kingdom

November 2016 - June 2018

StangaOne1

Web Development Intern

- Developing commercial websites.
- PHP, Laravel, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, JS, jQuery.

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

July 2016 - September 2016

Education

University of Essex

BSc Digital and Technology Solutions (Software Engineer)

Colchester, United Kingdom October 2016 – September 2019

Grade:

First-class honours degree with an award for highest degree mark in the computer science and electronic engineering department.

Capstone Project:

Developing algorithm for automatic hyperparameter optimisation and neural architecture search.

Relevant Modules:

- Software Engineering.
- Data Structures and Algorithms.
- Evolutionary Computation and Generic Programming.
- Advanced Programming.

Relevant Technologies:

- Java, C#, Python, C++.
- AWS, Microsoft Azure.
- Jenkins, Travis CI.

Big Data and Analytics Summer School

Delegate

- Learning Under Different Training and Testing Distributions.
- Visual recognition and tracking in large image and video datasets.
- Introduction to the Modelling and Analysis of Complex Systems.
- Artificial Intelligence and Neural Networks in Analytics.

High School of Mathematics

Secondary education

- Program with extensive study of Mathematics, English and IT.
- Graduated with excellence: 5.93 out of 6.

Colchester, United Kingdom

July 2018 - August 2018

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

September 2011 - June 2016

Awards and Certificates

Computer Science and Electronic Engineering Prize

University of Essex

 Awarded to the final year student who achieves the highest degree mark. Colchester, United Kingdom

July 2019

Tech Industry Gold Certificate of Recognition

Tech Partnership Degrees

• Nominated by the University of Essex for outstanding academic achievements and awarded by the Tech Partnership Degrees.

London, United Kingdom

June 2019

General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

Certificate of attainment

 $Colchester,\ United\ Kingdom$

April 2019

Information Security

Certificate of attainment

 $Colchester,\ United\ Kingdom$

April 2019

The Degree Apprenticeship Prize

University of Essex

Colchester, United Kingdom

 $September\ 2018$

 \bullet Awarded to the $2^{\rm nd}$ year apprenticeship degree student with the best overall mark.

K.F. Bowden Memorial Prize

University of Essex

Colchester, United Kingdom

September 2017

• Awarded to the top 4 first year students, in CSEE, with the best overall year mark.

Award of Excellence

High School of Mathematics

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

June 2016

• Awarded for overall performance above 5.80 out of 6.

StangaOne1 Academy

Web Development Basics

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

January 2016 - May 2016

• PHP 5, MySQL, Git, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, HTML 5, CSS 3.